## GAUTAM SAPRE

gautamsapre@gmail.com | (617)396-1452 | 1704 Yellowthroat Dr. Little Elm, TX, 75068 | linkedin.com/in/gautam-sapre | github.com/gautamsapre | gautamssapre.com

### **SUMMARY**

Results-driven and passionate software developer experienced with Programming languages such as JAVA, Python (Django), C++, etc, and technologies such as Azure Devops, Git, Unix, etc. Enthusiastic web developer with experience in database management. Currently works as a Software Engineering Intern at Communications and Power Ind.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineering Intern, Communication and Power Industries (CPI)

Nov 2020 - Present

- Assisted in a data migration project which included working with Azure DevOps and IBM RTC.
- Created Pipelines and Deployments in Azure for CPI's product line, e.g. Netmac which is an Antenna Control System.
- Explored Automated Testing solution for CPI's software products, worked with Test Complete, and reduce efforts of Test-Engineers by 20%.

### Industry Lead, ACM - HackUTD

Dec 2019 - Feb 2021

- Managed a team of HackUTD Industry Coordinators to host the biggest hackathon in North Texas.
- Set up meetings and kept up to date with the teams work to make sure conflicts are getting cleared.
- Duties included maintaining relations with companies and accommodate their needs. And also figure out perks for each tier of the sponsorship packet. Contacted companies like Microsoft, Google, Walmart Tech, IBM, etc.

Tutor, Spider Smart

Jul 2019 - Nov 2020

- Responsible for updating required logs and student documentation to keep records accurate and current.
- Created a model to track student progress, it figures out students' progress till date and recommends POA.
- Taught SAT Math students, worked out problems and explained theories as needed.

## **PROJECTS**

## Intelligent Air Quality - Murata Manufacturing Co.

- Enhanced an occupancy estimator using data regarding air quality of a closed room. Led the front-end team to create a dynamic website to depict data produced by the machine learning models.
- Utilized the Django web framework in Python to display data and model estimations in an organized and eye-appealing fashion. Technologies Used: Django, Python, and ReactJS.

#### Carpool

- Created an android application that lets users match with people to carpool with who have similar commutes.
- Implemented a chat application that lets the users talk to people matched with. Utilized the Firebase database to store users' data. Technologies used: Java (Android Studio), Google Autocomplete API and Firebase

### TravelSecure

- Utilized blockchain technologies to implement an airline insurance app that refunds money instantly through cryptocurrency when flights are canceled/delayed.
- Incorporated Metamask API and learned more about blockchain technologies. Technologies used: Java, Blockchain, and Metamask API.

# **SKILLS**

Languages: JAVA, C++, Python, Javascript, NodeJS, Django, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Markdown, Mips

 ${\bf Technologies:}\ {\bf Git,\,Linux,\,Unix,\,Firebase}$ 

**Tools**: Azure Devops, Github, Postman, Trello, Jira, Command Line, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Slack, Microsoft Teams

Soft: Entrepreneurship, Project Management, Adaptability, Conflict resolution, Communication Skills, Mentorship

## Accomplishments

- Courses: C/C++ in a Unix Environment, Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Data Structures and Algorithms, Linear Algebra, Probability and Statistics in CS, Programming Languages, Advanced Algorithms, Virtual Reality
- Organizations: Association of Computing Machinery (HackUTD): Industry Lead, Artificial Intelligence Society: Operations Coordinator
- Awards: Academic Excellence Scholarship at the Honors Level Recipient

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science The University of Texas at Dallas Bachelor of Science, Computer Science The University of Texas at Dallas Aug 2021 - May 2023

Aug 2018 - May 2022